Guide to the Jay F. Rosenberg Papers, 1956-2008 ASP.2008.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Jay F. Rosenberg Papers
1956-2008
1975-2007
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Rosenberg, Jay F.
ASP.2008.02
12 Linear Feet (28 document boxes)
Jay Rosenberg's work focused on such philosophical topics as Epistemology, Metaphysics, Philosophy of Language, History of Philosophy and the philosophy of Wilfrid Sellars. As he worked closely with Wilfrid Sellars, the collection also contains manuscripts, correspondence, and photographs of Sellars, his colleagues at the University of Pittsburgh, and at conferences.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
These papers contain materials relating to the professional life of the American philosopher Jay Rosenberg, including manuscripts of his books and his professional articles, as well as drafts and outlines drawn from his teaching materials used in courses at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. There are also manuscripts that relate to the professional academic talks that he gave at conferences or at other universities, as well as to his administrative activities as a professor at a major research university. There are also letters derived from his professional correspondence. Books and articles from his library and reprint collection have been retained if they contain substantive annotations.
In addition to his own manuscripts and correspondence, the papers contain extensive materials from the work of Wilfrid Sellars, with whom Rosenberg studied while earning his Ph.D. at the University of Pittsburgh. This section of his archive contains photographs of not only Wilfrid Sellars, but other philosphers of science. These were often group photos taken at conferences.
Biography
Jay Frank Rosenberg was a prominent American philosopher active during the middle 20th century through the early part of the 21st century. He was born on April 18, 1942 in Chicago, Illinois, and died on February 21, 2008 in Chapel Hill, North Carolina. He spent the bulk of his professional career as a Professor of Philosophy at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. He was active as both a researcher and a teacher. His areas of philosophical research included Metaphysics, Epistemology, History of Philosophy, and Philosophy of Language.
Rosenberg was a graduate of Reed College where he earned a B.A. in 1963. He then took his Ph.D. in Philosophy from the University of Pittsburgh. His degree was conferred in 1966. He studied under Wilfrid Sellars. The title of his research dissertation was "A Study of the Determinable - Determinate Relationship."
Rosenberg published extensively over the course of his career and produced ten books and over 80 articles on various topics in philosophy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Regina Falten-Rosenberg and Leslie Rosenberg Thompson in 2008.
Previous Citation
Jay Rosenberg Papers, ASP.2008.02, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The Rosenberg Papers are arranged into eight series, some of which are divided into sub-series:
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Professional Talks
Series III. Rosenberg Manuscripts
Series IV. Manuscripts from Others
Series V. Teaching Materials
Series VI. Library - PrePrints and Reprints (annotated)
Series VII. Rosenberg's Miscellaneous Personal Papers
Series VIII. Wilfrid Sellars's Miscellaneous Personal Papers
Syllabi; Manuscripts (Document genre); Correspondence; Epistemology; Metaphysics; Philosophy; Philosophy -- History; Language and languages -- Philosophy; University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill -- Faculty; Sellars, Wilfrid; Rosenberg, Jay F.
- Correspondence, 1956-2001; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Rosenberg was a very active and productive philosopher. Hence his correspondence reflects the professional activities of a professor of philosophy; the correspondence series includes letters to and from other philosophers, as well as correspondence with publishers, professional societies such as the APA, and administrators.
  - Correspondence with Publishers, 1964-2001; 1.
    - Socrates and Philosophy (B.) Adventures in New Ideas, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Philosophical Association, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Philosophical Quarterly 1, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Philosophical Quarterly 2; Wittgenstein's Theory of Language as Picture (B), American Philosophical Quarterly, Vol. 5, No.1, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Philosophical Quarterly 3, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Philosophical Quarterly 4; What's Happening in Philosophy of Language Today?: A Metaphysician's Eye View (B.), American Philosophical Quarterly, Vol. 9, No. 1, Jun. 1972; Presented: University of Massachusetts, 15 May, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - American Philosophical Quarterly 5; Apperception and Sartre's "Pre-Reflective Cogito" (B.), American Philosophical Quarterly, Vol. 18, No. 3, pp. 255-259, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sellars (Companion Articles), Epistemology (B.); Blackwell, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Elusiveness of Categories, The Archimedean Dilemma, and The Nature of Man: A Study in Sellarsian Metaphysics (B.); Bobbs Merrill, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Canadian Journal of Philosophy 1, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Canadian Journal of Philosophy 2, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Canadian Journal of Philosophy 3; Why the Theory of Knowledge Isn't the Same as Epistemology and What It Might Be Instead, May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Determinable/Determinate, Self-Conscious, Sellars Companion Articles (Metaphysics) (B.); Blackwell Companion to Metaphysics, March 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - New Perspectives on the Tractatus (B.); Dialogue, Vol. IV, No. 4, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Comments on Leppakoski, "The Transcendental Schema" (B); Eighth International Kant Congress, Memphis, TN, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Wilfrid Sellars (Encyclopedia) (B.); Encyclopedia Britannica, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Tractarian States and Functional Explanation: Comments on Blackburn, "Losing Your Mind"; UNC-G Conference, Future of Folk Psychology, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - The Dispute on the Indeterminacy of Translation (B.); Handbuch Sprachphilosophie, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Synonymy and the Epistemology of Linguistics (B.); Inquiry Vol. 10, No. 4, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - The Journal of Philosophy 1, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - The Journal of Philosophy 2, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - The Journal of Value Inquiry, August 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Kluwer Academic Publishers 1; Comments on Bechtel "Levels of Description, and Explanation in Cognitive Science" (B.), Minds and Machines, Vol. 4, No. 1, pp. 27-57; LINC-G Colloquium, 1991-92, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Kluwer Academic Publishers 2; Rules and Regularities Revisited (B.); In Language, Art, and Mind: Essays in Appreciation and Analysis in Honor of Paul Ziff; ed. Dale Jamieson, pp. 23-37., 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - About Competence and Performance (B.); Linguistics and Philosophy, February 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Descartes Skeptical Argument (B.); Logical Analysis and History of Philosophy, Vol. 1, pp. 209-32, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Metaphilosophy, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 'I Think': Some Reflections On Kant's Paralogisms (B.); Midwest Studies in Philosophy, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - On Strawson: Sounds, Skepticism, and Necessity (B); Mind, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - NIAS 1; On Understanding the Difficulty in Understanding Understanding (B.), pp. 29-43 in Meaning and Understanding, ed. Herman Parret and Jacques Bouveresse; Walter de Gruyter, Berlin and New York, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - NIAS 2; Conversation and Intelligence (B.), 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - NOUS 1; Intentionality and Self in the Tractatus (B.); Nous, Vol. II, No. 4, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - NOUS 2, April 1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - NOUS 3; Russell on Negative Facts (B.); Nous, Vol. VI, No. 1, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - NOUS 4; Review of Ways of Worldmaking by Nelson Goodman, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - NOUS 5, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - How Not to Be Systematic; Three Case Studies; Paideia; World Congress, Boston, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - The Philosopher's Index 1; Notes on Goodman's Nominalism (B.); Philosophical Studies, Vol. XXI, Nos. 1-2, 1967, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - The Philosopher's Index 2, August 1969 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - The Philosopher's Index 3; The Problem of Evil Revisited-A Reply to Schlesinger (B.); Journal of Value Inquiry, Vol. IV, No. 3, pp. 212-218, Fall 1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - The Philosopher's Index 4; Wittgenstein's Self-Criticisms or "Whatever Happened to the Picture-Theory?" (B.); Nous, Vol. IV, No. 3, pp. 209-223; Presented University of Massachusetts, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - The Philosopher's Index 5, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - The Philosopher's Index 6, September 1974 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - The Philosopher's Index 7, December 1974 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - The Philosopher's Index 8, January 1976 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - The Philosopher's Index 9; The "Given" and How to Take It-Some Reflections on Phenomenal Ontology (B.); Conference on Metaphysical Explanation, SUNY Buffalo, 22-24, 1974, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - The Philosopher's Index 10, November 1977 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Philosophia 1, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Philosophia 2; One Way of Understanding Time (B.); Philosophia, Vol. 2, No. 4, pp. 283-301, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Philosophia 3; Rules and Realism Redux: A Reply to Hannah (B.); Philosophia, 23, pp. 309-322, 1992, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Philosophical Papers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Philosophical Perspectives 1; Another Look at Proper Names (B.), 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Philosophical Perspectives 2; Phenomenological Ontology Revisited: A Bergmannian Retrospective (B.), 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Philosophical Quarterly; Tensed Discourse and the Eliminability of Tenses; The Philosophical Quarterly, Vol. 16, No. 63, 1964, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - The Philosophical Review 1, August 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - The Philosophical Review 2; The Concept of Linguistic Correctness (B.), May 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - The Philosophical Review 3, January 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Philosophical Studies, August 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Philosophical Studies 2; Reply to Stroud (B.); Vol. 31, pp. 117-121, 1976-77 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Philosophical Studies 3; Perception vs. Inner Sense: A Problem About Direct Awareness (B.), July 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Philosophy and Phenomenological Research 1; Raiders of the Lost Distinction: Richard Rorty and the Search for the Last Dichotomy (B.), December 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Philosophy and Phenomenological Research 2; Brandom's Making It Explicit: A First Encounter (B.); Pacific APA, PPR, 1995-96 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Philosophy and Phenomenological Research 3; Comments on Peter Van Inwagen, Material Beings (B.), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - A Note on the Ethical Implications of Psychiatric Diagnosis (B.); Psychiatric Diagnosis, ed. Joseph Agassi: (Philadelphia) pp. 165-74; Psychiatric Diagnosis, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Reidel 1; Castaneda's Ontology (B.), 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Reidel 2, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Reidel 3; Comparing the Incommensurable: Another Look at Convergent Realism (B.), April 1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - The Review of Metaphysics 1, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - The Review of Metaphysics 2, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - The Review of Metaphysics 3, July 1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - The Review of Metaphysics 4, May 1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Routledge 1, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Routledge 2; Sellars (Dictionary Entry) (B.), October 1993 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Routledge 3; Sellars (Encyclopedia Entry) (B.), 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Routledge 4; Kant and the Problem of Simultaneous Causation (B.); International Journal of Philosophic Studies, Vol. 6, No. 2, pp. 167-188, March 1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - F.M. Adams and the Modern Mind-A Philosophical Rencontre (B.); Rowman and Allenheld, December 1987 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Russell and the Form of Outer Sense (B.); Bertrand Russell Memorial Volume, ed: George W. Roberts, George Adlen and Unwin. and Humanities Press, Inc., London and New York, pp. 285-303; Russell Memorial Volumes, 1973, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Kantian Schemata and the Unity of Perception (B.); Sprache und Denken, Alex Burri, ed. (Walter de Gruyter; Berlin and NY); Sprache und Denken, January 1997 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - On Not Knowing What or Who One Is: Reflections on the Intelligibility of Dualism (B.); TOPOI, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - How Not to Misunderstand Peirce (B.); in R. Schantz, ed. "What is Truth?", Walter de Gruyter, pp. 283-98; Walter de Gruyter Gmblt & Co.KG, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Wilfrid Sellars' Philosophy of Mind; University of Oslo, June 1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Remarks on Heresies and Humpty Dumpty (B.); Comments on: Landesman: "Remarks on Reference and Action", Oberlin Colloquium; In: Issues in the Philosophy of Language, ed. by Alfred F. MacKay and Daniel D. Merrill, Yale University Press, pp. 119-128; Yale University Press, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence with Individuals and Institutions, 1961-1994; 2.
    - Barber, Ken, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Baldwin, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bechtel, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Butchvarov, Panayot, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Castaneda, Hector 1; Correspondence between Hector Castaneda and Wilfrid Sellars on Philosophy of Mind, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Castaneda, Hector 2, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Corrado, Jack, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Darraugh, Michelle, November 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Transcendental Arguments Revisited (B.); Falk, W.D., January 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Hardin, Larry, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Harman, Gilbert, February 1970 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bransen, Jan, July 1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Feldman, Fred, September 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Johnsen, Bredo, May 1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Landesman, Charles, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Linsky, March 1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Millikan, February 1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Science and the Epistemic Authority of Logical Analysis (B.); Rescher, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Bergmann on Time-Showing and Saying (B.); Mind, Vol. LXXVII, No. 306; Ryle, Gilbert, 1965, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Sellars, Wilfrid 1, March 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Sellars, Wilfrid 2, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Sellars, Wilfrid 3, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Sellars, Wilfrid 4; The Place of Color in the Scheme of Things: A Roadmap to Sellars' Carus Lectures (B.); The Monist, June 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Tait, Foster, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Yoes, M.G., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence about Conferences, 1968-1998; 3.
    - American Philosophical Association Western Division, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Linguistic Roles and Proper Names (B.); In: Queries and Rejoinders: The Philosophy of Wilfrid Sellars; Sellars Workshop, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Scrutinizing a Trade, Comments on Fogelin, SOFIA; Sociedad Filosofica Ibero Americana (SOFIA) Conference, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sellars' Correspondence, 1956-1981; 4.
    Rosenberg saved correspondence that Sellars had with various other philosophers, scientists, and scholars. These augment similar letters found in the ASP's Sellars Papers.
    - Sellars and Albriton, Rogers, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sellars and Bogen, Jim, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Sellars and Brumbaugh, Robert, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Sellars and Hendel, Charles W., Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Sellars and Margenau, Henry, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sellars and Marras, Ausonio, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Sellars and Peake, Charles H., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence Between David Rosenthal and Wilfrid Sellars on Intentionality; Sellars and Rosenthal, David, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Sellars and J.C.C. Smart; Sellars and Smart, Jack, February 1964 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with David Solomon "Thought and Action"; Sellars and Solomon, David, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Sellars and Weigand, Herman J., 1958 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Sellars and Zimmerman, Earl, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Sellars' Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1958-59,1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1976, 1980; 5.
    - Pat, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Fred, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Bill, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Professional Talks, 1970-2002; II.
  This series contains manuscripts of professional talks given by Rosenberg. There are Carus Lecture manuscripts, the manuscript of talks on Sellars philosophy, and talks on other philosophical topics.
  - Academic, 1977-2002; 1.
    - Chisholm, Roderick: Psychological Properties, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - de Vries, Willem: Sellars, Animals, and Thought, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Descartes: The First Modern Philosopher, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Euthanasia and the Sanctity of Life, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Reflections on Creativity, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Carus Lectures for 1977-8; Sellars, Wilfrid: Is Consciousness Physical?, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - The Carus Lectures for 1977-8; Sellars, Wilfrid: The Lever of Archimedes, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - The Carus Lectures for 1977-8; Sellars, Wilfrid: Naturalism and Process, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sellars, Wilfrid: Naturalism and Process, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Conference Reports, 1967-2001; 2.
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Comments on Kearn's "Sentences and Propositions", APA, Eastern Div. Mtgs., December 1967 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Comments on Kearn's "Sentences and Propositions", APA, Eastern Div. Mtgs. (Notes), December 1967 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Comments on Clayton's Identity and Exact Similarity, APA, December 1970 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Comments on Aune Sellars' Two Images of the World, APA Eastern Division; Boston, MA, December 1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Comments on Mathias Steup Foundationalism, Sense-Experiential Content and Sellars' Dilemma Pacific Division APA, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Comments on Rescher's "Scientific Truth and the Arbitrament of Praxis", Western APA, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Rosenberg, Jay: Comments on Butchvarov, "The Ontology of Philosophical Analysis", Western APA, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Rosenberg Manuscripts, 1966-1997; III.
  This series contains philosophical manuscripts written by Rosenberg throughout his professional career. These manuscripts include journal articles, invited book chapters, reviews, and conference papers. Unpublished manuscripts contain mostly handwritten and typed content along with sources Rosenberg may have used during his research and writing process.
  - Rosenberg Journal Articles, 1966-1997; 1.
    - "Brandom's Making It Explicit: A First Encounter", 1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "Comments on Peter Van Inwagen's Material Beings", 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Comparing the Incommensurable: Another Look at Convergent Realism, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Russell on Negative Facts, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Speaking Lions, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Tensed Discourse and the Eliminability of Tenses; Copyright Date, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "Wittgenstein's Self-Criticisms or Whatever Happened to the Picture Theory?", 1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Rosenberg Invited Chapters, 1975-1996; 2.
    - A Note on the Ethical Implications of Psychiatric Diagnosis, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Another Look at Proper Names, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Determinate/Determinable, Self-Consciousness Sellars Companion Articles (Metaphysics), 1995 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - The Dispute on the Indeterminacy of Translation, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - The Elusiveness of Categories, The Archimedean Dilemma, and the Nature of Man: A Study in Sellarsian Metaphysics, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - E.M. Adams and the Modern Mind: A Philosophical Rencontre, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - On a Certain Antinomy, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Russell and the Form of Outer Sense, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Socrates and Philosophy, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Tractarian States and Folk-Psychological Explanation, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Transcendental Arguments and Pragmatic Epistemology (German), Undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Rosenberg Reviews, 1972, 1984; 3.
    - Language, Thought, and Other Biological Categories, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Reviews on Rosenberg's "The Thinking Self", Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Review of On Universals by Nicholas Wolterstorff; The Philosophical Review LXXXI, 3: pp. 382-387, July 1972 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Rosenberg Proceedings, 1996; 4.
    - Comments on Leppakoski, The Transcendental Schemata, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Rosenberg Unpublished Manuscripts, 1958-1984; 5.
    - A Brief View From the Metalanguage, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - A Philosophical Investigation of the Theory of Reference Group Analysis, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Color Incompatibilities and Natural Necessity, Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Comments on Parsons: A Meinong Analysis of Fictional Objects, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Function of General Laws in Science; Thesis, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Henry Louis Mencken As a Philosopher, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Objects, Substance, and the Thing-In-Itself, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Passionate Philosophers and the Passions of Philosophy: Response to C.H. Seigfried, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Peirce's Theory of Thought, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "Remarks on Jurgen Mittelstrass' Uber Transzendental", Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Self, Selves, and Self-Knowledge--An Excursion Through the Critique of Pure Reason, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Some Reflections on the Aim, Province, and Possibility of Deontic Logic, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - "Some Remarks Inspired by 'Erotic Language'", Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Some Too Brief Remarks on Deductivism and Its Critics, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - W.D. Falk: Ought Judgments, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Philosophical Notes and Notebooks, 1965-1992; 6.
    - Epistemology: Stroud, Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Wittgenstein: Tractatus (Notes), Undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Philosophical Notebooks, 10 items, 1965-1992 (Box 10)
- Manuscripts from Others, 1931-1982; IV.
  Manuscripts from others contains a number of philosophical manuscripts written by Wilfrid Sellars. Manuscripts written by other philosophers are also included in this series.
  - Manuscripts by Wilfrid Sellars, 1947-1982; 1.
    - Meaning as Functional Classification (A Perspective on the Relation of Syntax to Semantics), Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Mental Events, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The Monist, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - More on Givenness and Explanatory Coherence, Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - More on Givenness and Explanatory Coherence (2), Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Naming and Saying, Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Naturalism and Ontology, Undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Naturalism and Process, Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Intentionality; The Journal of Philosophy, Vol. LXI, No. 21, pp. 655-666, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - On Accepting First Principles, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)